Venkataramana Solleti

Associate Director at Cognizant

Summary

An astute professional with impressive fast track management career, driven by challenges and desire to succeed, backed with 16 plus years of IT career reflecting strong leadership skills with hands-on experience in Program Management, People Management, Competency Development, Project Management, and Consulting & Software Development. Built, managed and delivered large engagements and programs across multiple locations, practices; substantial exposure in delivering Infrastructure, development, maintenance and testing projects. Possess domain knowledge in the areas of Banking, Finance, Securities, Insurance and Manufacturing. Envisioning usage of new technology and tailoring its usage for achieving desired results. Comprehensive experience in leading teams & managing multiple projects. Excellent client facing experience as an Onsite coordinator and Project and Program Manager for over 5 years.

IT Infrastructure Management, Remote Infrastructure Management, Program Management, Service Delivery, Service Management, Managed Services, Technical Design and Project Management

Experience

Associate Director at Cognizant

May 2015 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Pre-sales and Delivery Support for the Solution

Analyze the Customer data and review the Solution Architects inputs on the solution

Review the solution for the customer requirements

ITSM and Service Delivery Inputs

Delivery Manager at Wipro

April 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 2 months)

- # Manage Fixed Price projects, Managed Services and Staff Augmentation
- # Successfully improved the Customer Satisfaction (CSAT) index through innovative value additions to customers
- # Improve the productivity through lean, Automation and Service Improvement Programs
- # SLA Complaince
- # Daily health checks and avoid outages
- # Effective Change Management and zero Change violations

- # Reduce the incidents through problem management
- # Cost of Delivery reduction through the improved rookie ratio and onsite head account reduction
- # Manage the Major Incidents effectively and reduce the down time
- # People Management with rewards & recognition, Competency Development, Rotation and Hygiene.
- # Role out Service Assurance and MEP and execute
- # Implement Automation to increase the productivity and reduce the project cost.
- # Define and set performance Goals and Objectives.
- # Stake holders management, Relationship Management
- # Reduce the inefficiencies, setup, Simplify and optimize the processes

Program Manager at Wipro Technologies

May 2009 - March 2013 (3 years 11 months)

Heads the Technology Infrastructure Services Mainframe Division of Wipro Technologies.

Responsible for the growth, Service Improvement plans, New initiatives, Skill development.

Heads 300 strong team in Mainframe Infrastructure services which involves System Administrators, DBAs,

Operators, Schedulers and Production Support staff.

Project Manager at UBS Stamford at Wipro Technologies

December 2005 - February 2006 (3 months)

Responsible for

Planning and execution and delivery of the entire release

Interacting with the client and business.

Managing the risk, Billing, Status reporting to the management and client.

Monitoring Performance tuning of Database and SQLs.

Managing the overall work plan to ensure work is assigned and completed on time and within budget.

Project Manager at Pitney Bowes at Wipro Technologies

October 2004 - December 2005 (1 year 3 months)

Responsible for

Planning and execution and delivery of the entire release

Defining and collecting metrics to give a sense for how the project is progressing and whether the deliverables produced are acceptable.

Managing risk, Billing and status reporting.

Gathering requirements. Created the functional specifications.

Managing scope to ensure that only what was agreed to is delivered, unless changes are approved through scope management.

Coordinating with subject matter experts, leading in SIEBEL, SAP, MQ areas and the vendor to client Canon.

Delivered the project with ZERO productions issues.

Skills & Expertise

Vendor Management

Requirements Analysis

Project Management

Management

ITIL

PMP

Project Planning

SDLC

Program Management

Software Project Management

Pre-sales

Mainframe

Solution Architecture

Global Delivery

Risk Management

Delivery Management

Program Delivery Management

Infra Delivery Manager

People Management

Customer Engagement

Service Delivery Management

Operations Management

Incident Management

IT Transformation

Lean Transformation

IT Strategy

IT Service Management

Service Delivery

Data Center

Enterprise Architecture

CRM

Outsourcing

Project Delivery

PMO

Project Management Office (PMO)

Education

Sri Venkateswara University

B Tech, Engineering, 1989 - 1993

Venkataramana Solleti

Associate Director at Cognizant



1 person has recommended Venkataramana

"As a colleague I have seen Venkat work to perfection on the projects. He is very good at people management and client management. He always strives to provide exceptional service to the client. He is known to be very methodical and process oriented. Also another unique quality is he keeps himself abreast with happenings in technology. He is always looking for new learning's and opportunities to hone his skills in project management and technology."

— Mahesh Vecham, worked directly with Venkataramana at Wipro Technologies

Contact Venkataramana on LinkedIn